About Me

I am well-organised and hardworking, always putting the maximum into whatever I do. I have been passionate about computers and programming from a young age and have endeavoured to progress my skills at every stage.

I have programming experience with Java and Python, and have learned web app development (HTML, PHP, CSS, JS w/ jQuery & AJAX) on my own initiative using Amazon Web Services. My work has also given me Java experience with Maven and Spring, as well as app developer experience with React Native and Expo.

Education

University of Glasgow - 2016 to Present

On track for a first-class honours in BSc
Computing Science (GPA 20.75/22.0)
Awarded the Level 3 (third year) Honours
Prize for highest overall grades
Straight A's in first and third year
Won first prize in the 2017 Morgan Stanley
Hackathon challenge (second prize in 2019) and
the 2018 Glasgow Cyber Defence Exercise
Treasurer for GUBMS

Dunoon Grammar School - 2014 to 2016

Advanced Higher Grades: 2 A's Higher Grades: 5 A's, 1 B

Skills (in order of fluency)

Programming Languages

Java, Python, JavaScript (jQuery + AJAX), PHP, HTML, MySQL, SQL Server, CSS, H2, C++

Services & Other Skills

AWS, React Native, Expo, WordPress, WooCommerce, Zapier, OneSignal, Maven, Spring, Twilio, Photoshop

Work Experience

Barclays - May 2019 to September 2019

Improved code quality of a legacy system, identifying and fixing several critical bugs, now in production

Set up Java servlets using Spring, Maven and Apache Tomcat instances

GoEatDirect - December 2018 to Present

Cross-platform app developer & publisher AWS server(s) admin Configured WordPress websites w/ WooCommerce integration

Automated several manual tasks including menu parsing & creation

Implemented & managed push notifications
Created metrics monitoring dashboard

Nutriplotter - October 2018 to May 2019

University Project, hired after completion to continue work as sole developer

Developed nutritional app from scratch, including database integration

Three in One Dunoon - October 2015 to April 2016

Learned to deal with customers both in person and over the phone
Time management skills from handling orders and balancing work with school
Experienced working as part of a team

Relevant Projects

Created a YouTube playlist service that allows users to create rooms and add videos to a queue by voting (max.ardeer.co.uk/playlist)

(Private WIP) Creating an aggregated system that queries different distributed recommender algorithms to provide a better recommendation.

Other projects hosted at:

max.ardeer.co.uk, github.com/maxburton